beaut.ie 2019-11-01

# Privacy Policy | Beaut.ie

This website, Beaut.ie, www.beaut.ie and associated apps is owned and operated by Packed House Ltd.

In this Privacy Policy, when we refer to “Beaut.ie”, we mean the digital network operated by Beaut.ie, or its parent companies, subsidiaries and affiliates.

Beaut.ie is fully compliant with The General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) (EU) 2016/679, which came into effect on May 25th 2018.

**Right to Privacy**

Beaut.ie respects your right to privacy and are transparent on what data we collect & how we use it. Any information we collect, be it non-personalised or personalised, will be treated with the highest standards of security and confidentiality, strictly in accordance with The General Data Protection Regulation. Beaut.ie strictly only works with fully GDPR compliant partners.

**Advertising Change of Consent**

Beaut.ie respects your right to choose. Consent revocation is the process by which EEA (European Economic Area) visitors who consented to personalized ads can revoke that consent.  
Click here to revoke your choice.

**Collection and use of personal information**

Beaut.ie uses some third party software and systems to carry out tasks related to the operation of the website – for example Google. A Data Protection Impact assessment has been carried out prior to any third party software being utilised, and data processing agreements have been entered into with all such service providers. Beaut.ie strictly only uses GDPR compliant service providers.

Beaut.ie collects non-personalised and personalised data in three main ways:

Information that you actively volunteer or opt into, such as email newsletter registration, browser or app notifications and similar.

Analytics: This allows Beaut.ie to measure the number of visits to the website, how content is consumed and helps inform us as to how to improve the website for visitors.

Advertising: Advertisers on Beaut.ie may use cookies to inform, optimise and serve ads based on your browsing activities and interests.

We never share first party / personally identifiable information from Beaut.ie website or associated apps with any third parties without your explicit consent.

For more information on how to manage your cookies please visit our [Cookie Policy](https://www.beaut.ie/cookie-policy).

**The information we collect:**

**Advertising**

Advertisements on Beaut.ie can be of a non-personalised or personalised nature. The information collected by advertisers helps them to gauge the effectiveness of their campaigns, provide you with more relevant advertisements and may limit the number of times you see an advertisement. Upon visiting Beaut.ie for the first time, you will have the choice to receive personalised or non personalised advertisements. You may change this choice at any time by visiting our Advertising Change of Consent in our Privacy Policy. For more information and details of how to manage how advertising works on Beaut.ie, read our [Cookies Policy](https://www.beaut.ie/cookie-policy).

**Email Newsletters**

You may register for informational email newsletters via our website. This requires your name and email address, and optionally your county and areas of interest, to be submitted to our email newsletter software (Mailchimp), which is fully compliant with The General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). Read Mailchimp's [Privacy Policy](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/).  
You may choose to opt out of email newsletters or update your preferences at any time via the unsubscribe link in the foot of any of our email newsletters. You may also choose to opt out by contacting [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) at any time.

**Email Contact by You**

If you email Beaut.ie with feedback or questions, we will respond to you as quickly as possible. Any details you send to us, including email and name, are stored for as long as is necessary to deal with your query. All contacts are deleted once we have satisfactorily answered your question or comment.

**Services We Use**

We use selected third party services on our website. We only use GDPR compliant services and partners.

**Analytics Services**

These services help us build a better website experience. We use [Google Analytics](https://policies.google.com/privacy), [Hotjar](https://www.hotjar.com/legal/policies/privacy), [Firebase](https://firebase.google.com/support/privacy/) and [Permutive](https://permutive.com/privacy/) for this purpose. Hotjar anonymises your IP and does not contain any personally identifiable information. Google Analytics and Firebase does capture some personal information, such as location information. Permutive collects IP addresses and a non personalised Permutive ID number to analyse what type of content is consumed to help provide more relevant content groups for our readers. Read their Privacy Policies & options on how to opt out by clicking on the links above. These companies do not share your data with any other companies. No personal data collected by any of the analytics services we employ will be disclosed to any other third party, unless obliged to do so by a rule of law or directly opted in to allow so by the user.

**Advertising**

We schedule our advertising on site and in app with Google's Ad Manager. We use Permutive to help build audience groupings. You can read more about Permutive in their [Privacy Policy](https://permutive.com/privacy/). Any information collected and stored can be of a personalised or non-personalised nature; you have the option to choose your preference when visiting our website for the first time and you can change your preferences at any time in our Privacy Policy. Some cookies are used for non personalised ads. Read our [Cookies Policy](https://www.beaut.ie/cookie-policy) for more information on advertising.

**Competitions & Surveys:**

**Wufoo**

Beaut.ie occasionally uses a third party, Wufoo for competition entry collection. We will clearly inform you when we are using this service. Wufoo is owned and operated by Survey Monkey. Read Wufoo’s [Privacy Policy](https://www.surveymonkey.com/mp/legal/privacy-policy/).

**Survey Monkey**

Beaut.ie occasionally uses Survey Monkey to run reader surveys. We will clearly inform you when we are using this service. Read Survey Monkey’s [Privacy Policy](https://www.surveymonkey.com/mp/legal/privacy-policy/).

**Social Media & Website Players**

Beaut.ie offers readers the opportunity to share and view our content on various social media platforms, including Facebook, Twitter, Pinterest, Whatsapp, Instagram & Flickr. We use a third party to help manage our social media audience and create better targeted content to our followers and website readers. You can read more about any of the third party providers below.

Facebook both acts as a data controller and a data processor for Beaut.ie. We use Facebook [Custom Audiences](https://www.facebook.com/legal/terms/customaudience) to group users of Beaut.ie into interest audiences if they are logged into Facebook and engage either with any of  Beaut.ie’s Facebook posts, or engage with content on the Beaut.ie website, by use of a tracking pixel. We do this to better present audiences with more relevant content, be it editorial or advertising content. Any information collected is either of a non personal nature, or if personalised then the information is anonymised by Facebook, as per their [terms of use](https://www.facebook.com/legal/terms/customaudience). You can opt in or out of such functionality when registering an account with Facebook or opt in to any such services Facebook offers. Furthermore, you can view and manage any websites that have access to your information by using the “[Off Facebook Activity](https://www.facebook.com/off-facebook-activity)” tool.

When connecting your Facebook account to Beaut.ie to comment on an article, we need to obtain permission to collect your associated Facebook name, email address and IP address.  
Comments on Beaut.ie are moderated. If a comment breaks our house rules we may need to remove a comment or block a user from commenting in the future. We need this account information to provide this service.

You may delete any of your comments at any time by visiting the post that you commented on and removing the comment. You may also disconnect Beaut.ie’s integration from your [Facebook page](https://www.facebook.com/help/211829542181913?helpref=faq_content).

Beaut.ie also uses GDPR compliant third party audio and video players as well as quiz generating tools. These include Youtube, Omnyplayer, Blue Billywig and Playbuzz.

Such third party services are subject to change. Any additions or removals will be updated in this section.

You can read each of their Privacy Policies by visiting:

**External Links**

Beaut.ie does provide links to other websites. Whilst we do check the validity of other websites and never link to any bogus websites, you should always check other website’s own Privacy Policies and Terms of Use.

**Data Protection**

We update our Privacy Policy from time to time as legislation and internal operating procedures change. Please keep an eye on this page for any updates or changes.  
Contact our Data Protection Officer at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) for any further clarifications or personal data requests. Whilst we aim to address any questions or queries as soon as possible, please allow up to 30 working days for a response.

For more information on data protection, please visit [www.dataprotection.ie](https://www.dataprotection.ie/) & <https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection_en>

Last updated: 28/08/2019
